Anuj Kumar Agrawal



Email: herranuj@gmail.com Mobile: +91-7760735000

Brief Background

I have 16 years of experience as a German language specialist and 3000 plus hours as a German language teacher. I am currently teaching German language as a freelancer in Mercedes Benz, Bangalore since November, 2015.

Prior to this, I have worked in PA Consulting, IBM and Hewlett Packard.

Primary expertise

 German Language Specialist and teacher.

Related experience

- Marketing Skills
- Expert Search Services for Business Information
- Business Newsletter Services
- Telemarketing / Primary Research
- Processing of Financial Documents
- Teaching German
- Cross-Cultural Training.

Qualifications

- Oberstufe, Goethe Institut, Germany (2003)
- Master of Arts in German Jawaharlal Nehru University, New Delhi, India. (1998-2000)

Primary expertise

German Language Specialist and **teacher**- *Taught German language and* used verbal and writing skills over a wide spectrum of marketing activities, outsourced knowledge and business process operations.

Related Experience

- Marketing Skills Plan and execute end-to-end multi-touch campaigns for Germany, co-ordinating with suppliers, business partners and internal stakeholders to achieve desired business results.
- Expert Search Services for Business Information can swiftly understand and efficiently retrieve comprehensive but useful data from various databases to support consultants / clients over the entire cycle of selling, operating and developing consulting assignments.
- Newsletter Services cater to the demand from consultants / clients for market, sector, industry and geography-specific business information aligned to the firm's key capabilities and designed to spot business opportunities and threats.
- **Telemarketing Skills** from building contact databases to running campaigns to sell software solutions in German-speaking countries.
- *Transaction Processing* expertise on the different phases of the purchase administration cycle, from processing purchase requests to invoice payment.
- Teaching, Training and Interpretation combining a set of German culturespecific soft skills to improve the quality of interaction between Germans and non-Germans.

Anuj Kumar Agrawal

Email: herranuj@gmail.com Mobile: +91-7760735000

Key experience

- Freelancing (2015-) Teaching German language in Mercedes-Benz.
- IBM (2010-2015) Digital Marketing and Sales Operations.
- PA Consulting (2008-2010) Retrieving and collating business information for consultants, detailed primary research over the phone to build databases as well as to pull out specific business information and running business newsletter services on different companies and business sectors.
- IBM Rational Software (formerly Telelogic) (2005-2008) Telemarketing of software solutions to German-speaking countries. Experience of independently managing all telemarketing activities, including building prospect databases from the Internet. Also ran cross-cultural training workshops for colleagues from Sales and Support to help them understand German culture and thereby improve the quality of their interactions with their German colleagues.
- Hewlett Packard BPO (2003-2005) Processing of purchase orders and invoices. Was a key member of the team which transitioned the entire purchase administration process for HP Germany from Spain to India. Know how the purchase administration cycle works, how purchase requests are processed and how payments are made on invoices.